<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Will Jarrard</title>
    <link>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Will Jarrard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>wej5ar@virginia.edu (Will Jarrard)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wej5ar@virginia.edu (Will Jarrard)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>
Clothes Recommendation System Using Collaborative Filtering</title>
      <link>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/post/2022-06-29-clothes-recommendation-system-using-collaborative-filtering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wej5ar@virginia.edu (Will Jarrard)</author>
      <guid>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/post/2022-06-29-clothes-recommendation-system-using-collaborative-filtering/</guid>
      <description>Code can be found here.
Abstract Businesses and retailers are constantly faced with the challenge of predicting their customers’ buying behavior. As the realm of machine learning progresses, retailers can predict consumer behavior via recommendation algorithms. Both stakeholders, customers and businesses, benefit from a better prediction algorithm as customers are recommended more of their likes and businesses increase their profit margins. Using an ALS Implicit model, we achieved a mean average precision (MAP) of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying Songs with NLP</title>
      <link>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/post/2022-06-29-classifying-songs-with-nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wej5ar@virginia.edu (Will Jarrard)</author>
      <guid>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/post/2022-06-29-classifying-songs-with-nlp/</guid>
      <description>Github and code can be found here.
Problem Statement Music genres organize music into collections by indicating similarities between different songs. Many music streaming services such as Spotify have high incentives to automate the classification process since they have an estimated 60,000 new songs uploaded onto their site daily. Currently, many music streaming services leverage metadata such as acoustics and emotional tone for genre classification because audio files are more useful than lyrics in terms of classifying a song, due to the high dimensionality of the audio files and low dimensionality of the lyrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resampling</title>
      <link>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/post/2022-06-29-resampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wej5ar@virginia.edu (Will Jarrard)</author>
      <guid>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/post/2022-06-29-resampling/</guid>
      <description> Required R packages and Directories data.dir = &amp;#39;https://mdporter.github.io/DS6030/data/&amp;#39; # data directory library(R6030) # functions for DS-6030 library(tidyverse) # functions for data manipulation library(FNN) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wej5ar@virginia.edu (Will Jarrard)</author>
      <guid>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I just received a masters in data science seeking a full-time position in data science or machine learning engineering. I am experienced contributor in the biotech industry working on infrastructure projects and predictive models such as a two year project of helping a hospital in Rwanda digitize their medical records. I have experience in statistical analysis, machine learning and deep learning with tools including Pandas/Spark/Pytorch/Tensorflow in Python, tidyverse in R, and SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Projects</title>
      <link>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/page/pythonprojects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wej5ar@virginia.edu (Will Jarrard)</author>
      <guid>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/page/pythonprojects/</guid>
      <description>Classifying songs with NLP Web scraped song lyrics to predict songs genres utilizing statistical learning methods such as multinomial logistic regression, naive bayes and linear SVC. Also utilized newer deep learning NLP methods such as GRU’s, CNN’s, basic transformers, and BERT.
Clothes Recommendation System Using Collaborative Filtering Created a recommendation system in PySpark using ALS modeling to recommend clothes a person is likely to buy next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Projects</title>
      <link>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/page/rprojects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wej5ar@virginia.edu (Will Jarrard)</author>
      <guid>https://wejarrard.github.io/my_blog/page/rprojects/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
